whatsonstage.com 2012-12-31

# Whatsonstage.com - UK's Leading Theatre Site for Discount Tickets, News, Listings & More

This constitutes the Privacy Policy of whatsonstage.com ("the Website") which is operated by Bandwidth Communications ("our", "us" and "we") which is a company registered in England and Wales and is part of the Time Out Group (registration number 01782049). Our registered office and postal address is C/O Time Out Group, Universal House, 251-255 Tottenham Court Road, London W1T 7AB, England.

Whatsonstage.com is subject to all applicable laws and regulations relating to the protection of personal data and privacy in the United Kingdom including (without limitation) the EU Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC, the EU Directive on privacy and Electronic Communications 2002/58/EC, the Data Protection Act 1998, the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000, the Data Protection (Processing of Sensitive personal data) Order 2000 and all other industry guidelines (whether statutory or non-statutory) or Codes of Practice issued by the Information Commissioner relating to the processing of personal data or privacy or any amendments and re-enactments thereof.

Whatsonstage.com has developed this privacy policy to demonstrate a firm commitment to privacy and to disclose the information gathering and sharing practices for [www.whatsonstage.com](http://www.whatsonstage.com/) and Bandwidth Communications.

**Notice of Collection of Data**  
By visiting whatsonstage.com, you accept the practices described in this privacy policy and consent to the collection and use of your personal data by us for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy and for any other purpose reasonably necessary for the provision or proper administration of whatsonstage.com and the business of Bandwidth Communications.

If you do not accept the practices set out in this Privacy Policy you should not use whatsonstage.com.

Whatsonstage.com will consider its Privacy Policy from time to time which may develop and evolve over time, and this policy may change to reflect that. We will use personal data in accordance with the Privacy Statement under which that personal data was collected. You should periodically revisit the whatsonstage.com privacy policy to be sure you are familiar with the current policy. Use of whatsonstage.com following any modifications to the privacy policy will be conclusively deemed as acceptance of the terms of this privacy policy and any changes to the policy both in connection with personal data previously collected and that collected following any changes to this Privacy Policy. Nothing in this privacy policy is meant to impede Whatsonstage.com's right or ability to transfer, sell or otherwise dispose of any of its assets.

Please note that whatsonstage.com may contain links to other websites which are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy even though they may feature the Whatsonstage.com logo because of a marketing agreement with Whatsonstage.com. If you access other sites using the links provided, the operators of those sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours. You should look for the specific privacy statement on any such co-branded page. Whatsonstage.com cannot be held responsible for the privacy policies of other companies. Whatsonstage.com recommends you review the privacy policy of any site visited on the Internet.

Please also note that where Whatsonstage.com make available chat rooms, forums, message boards, and news groups that personal data that you disclose in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any information on them.

**What data is being collected?**  
If you are merely visiting the public areas of whatsonstage.com, we do not collect any personal data about you, however, we may automatically collect information about your visits, such as browsing patterns. Information collected in this way does not reveal your contact details or any type of personal data. This information is only used in aggregate form to analyse, manage and develop whatsonstage.com and is not linked to any individual.

We collect personally identifiable information, like names, postal addresses, email addresses, etc., when voluntarily submitted by our visitors. If you choose to fill out any reader surveys, enter a competition, apply for an offer or make a purchase from our online shop, you will be asked to supply some information about yourself, including your name, address, phone number and email address.

Whatsonstage.com also collects the details provided by you on registration together with information we learn about you from your use of our service and your visits to whatsonstage.com and other sites accessible from it. We also collect information about the transactions you undertake including details of payment cards used.

If you enter a competition you should read the terms and conditions of that promotion which will confirm how we will use any personal data submitted as part of the entry to the competition. By entering a competition or applying for an offer you give permission for Whatsonstage.com to pass your details to any third party sponsor of the competition / offer so they may contact you in the event that you win the competition or qualify for the offer. If you do not win the competition / qualify for the offer your details will not be passed on without your explicit permission.

We may also collect additional information in connection with information you provide when giving us feedback or completing profile forms.

**How we collect data**  
We collect data from information supplied by you. When you give whatsonstage.com your email address in response to marketing emails, you are asked to let whatsonstage.com know how it can be used. You may 'opt in' to receive regular email newsletters that contain information whatsonstage.com believe to be of value to you, specifically events, special discounts and offers selected by the Whatsonstage.com marketing department.

All marketing emails will contain a link to opt out of further communications from whatsonstage.com If you make a purchase via whatsonstage.com the assumption may be made that you will be interested in similar products and you may receive emails with information about these products. All marketing emails will contain a link to opt out of further communications from whatsonstage.com. For the avoidance of doubt you cannot opt out of service emails whatsonstage.com may also use cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered. Cookie and tracking technology are useful for gathering information such as browser type and operating system, tracking the number of visitors to whatsonstage.com, and understanding how visitors use whatsonstage.com. Cookies can also help customize whatsonstage.com for visitors. Whatsonstage.com uses cookies to track user usage on whatsonstage.com. Whatsonstage.com uses ad servers (such as DoubleClick) to serve advertisements on Whatsonstage.com. Ad servers use cookies to help target relevant ads to users.

Personal information cannot be collected via cookies and other tracking technology, however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. "Cookies" are small pieces of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enables the server to collect information from the browser. You can find out more about the way cookies work on http://www.cookiecentral.com.

We may also use uses cookies for a number of other purposes, for instance to enable us to simplify the logging on process for registered users, to help ensure the security and authenticity of registered users, to provide the mechanisms for improving and monitoring visitor's experiences mapping and to enable traffic monitoring.

Non-registered visitors of the site are sent anonymous cookies to keep track of their browsing patterns and build up a demographic profile. In addition, any visitor who has clicked on a whatsonstage.com advertisement on another site that links to whatsonstage.com will be sent anonymous cookies that will allow us to analyse advertising effectiveness and manage our relationship with affiliate sites.

Whilst you do not need to allow your browser to accept cookies in order to browse much of our web site or to access many of our services, you must have cookies enabled if you wish to shop online at any of our stores or access any areas reserved for registered users.

Most browsers allow you to turn off the cookie function. If you want to know how to do this please look at the help menu on your browser.

Whatsonstage.com cookies cannot be used by themselves to identify you and you have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, some interactive features of whatsonstage.com may not work if cookies are disabled. Cookies can be disabled in your browser by following the instructions found at: www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies.

**Why data is being collected?**  
We collect data for a number of reasons. It helps us tailor and personalise you experience with whatsonstage.com and enables us to send you relevant information about products or services that may be of interest to you. We may use data to send you offers and news about Bandwidth Communications products and services or those of other carefully selected companies which we think may be of interest to you. Your information may be passed to and used by all Whatsonstage.com licensees and affiliates.

Whatsonstage.com collects aggregate user information to sell sponsorships on whatsonstage.com to advertisers and to monitor customer traffic patterns such as the number of users to whatsonstage.com, the pages visited and the length of visit which enables us to improve the service we provide.

In addition, Whatsonstage.com collects information from users who click on advertisements to measure interest and inform advertisers as to how many users have seen or clicked on their ads.

Whatsonstage.com also uses demographic and preference information to allow advertising banners on whatsonstage.com to be targeted, in the aggregate, to the users for whom they are most pertinent.

**What we do with the information collected**  
The information you provide is used to fulfill your specific request unless you give us permission to use it in another manner, for example to add you to one of our mailing lists.

We will use your contact details to communicate with you.

We use personal data for the purpose of providing you with the services you have requested and to personalise our service to you. We may use your information to send you offers and news about Bandwidth Communications products and services or those of other carefully selected companies which we think may be of interest to you. Your information may be passed to and used by all Whatsonstage.com licensees and affiliates.

From time to time we may enter into a commercial arrangement with another company that is not owned by us to provide additional features. Whatsonstage.com may also, from time to time, use third party suppliers to provide part of our service to you. Any personal data that you provide when signing up on a co-branded page may be shared with our third party partner.

We may also use and disclose information in aggregate (so that no individual customers are identified) for marketing and strategic development purposes and aggregate cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties.

In some circumstances outside service providers may be based in countries outside the European Economic Area whose laws provide for a different standard of protection for your personal data than that provided under UK Law.

Save as explained above and subject to the provisions below Whatsonstage.com will not pass on your individual user details to third parties without asking for explicit permission.

Whatsonstage.com cooperates with all law-enforcement inquiries and reserves the right to disclose personally identifying or aggregate information to detect and prevent fraud and in connection with a subpoena or other court-sanctioned demand for such information.

We may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; or, (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or, (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place. The information is not provided to these companies for marketing purposes.

**How do we keep data secure?**  
Whatsonstage.com has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under whatsonstage.com's control. Only authorized employees, agents and contractors (who have agreed to keep information secure and confidential) have access to this information. All newsletters from this site allow you to opt out of further mailings. You can also opt out of further emails other than service emails which are an integral part of our service, such as purchase confirmations, invoice emails, and customer notices such as those relating to data management and similar purposes.

We use appropriate physical, electronic and managerial security measures to try to prevent that personal data from being accessed by unauthorised persons and to ensure that you may input personal data safely. This means that sometimes we may ask for proof of identity before we disclose personal data to you.

Only aggregate statistics about the number of users and their traffic patterns will be given to advertisers.

Individual user details will not be passed on without prior consent. If whatsonstage.com ever requests that you volunteer additional information, such as financial data or age (in an online survey, for example) your response will always be voluntary and this data will only be used as an aggregate of data in conjunction with users of whatsonstage.com as a whole.

Despite these efforts, whatsonstage.com cannot guarantee that a hacker will not obtain access to communications between users and whatsonstage.com.

**Requests for Personal Information**  
To obtain a copy of the personal information Bandwidth Communications holds about you and to contact Whatsonstage.com regarding this policy by post please address your request to The Data Controller, Time Out London, 251 Tottenham Court Road, London, W1T 7AB enclosing your cheque or postal order for £10 payable to Time Out Digital Limited.

January 2012
